// alt + q
let MCQS = [
  {
    question: "Who is the father of computer?",
    choice1: "James Gosling",
    choice2: "Charles Babbage",
    choice3: "Dennis Ritchie",
    choice4: "Bjarne Stroustrup",
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "The generation based on VLSI microprocessor",
    choice1: "1st",
    choice2: "2nd",
    choice3: "3rd",
    choice4: "4th",
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not a type of computer code",
    choice1: "EDIC",
    choice2: "ASCII",
    choice3: "BCD",
    choice4: "EBCDIC",
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not a type of computer on the basis of operation?",
    choice1: "Digital",
    choice2: "Analog",
    choice3: "Hybrid",
    choice4: "Remote",
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the indian institution has developed the SUPER COMPUTER PRATHAM?",
    choice1: "Wipro",
    choice2: "TCS",
    choice3: "C_DAK",
    choice4: "PRL",
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A light senesitive device that converts drawing, printed text or other images into digital form is_______",
    choice1: "Plotter",
    choice2: "OMR",
    choice3: "Scanner",
    choice4: "None of these",
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the decimal equivalent of the binary number 1011?",
    choice1: "23",
    choice2: "39",
    choice3: "42",
    choice4: "21",
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the full form of EEPROM?",
    choice1: "Electrically Erasable Programmble Read Only Memory",
    choice2: "Easily Erasable Programming Read Only Memory",
    choice3: "Electronic Erasable Programmble Read Only Memory",
    choice4: "None of these",
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A computer is accurate but if the result of a computation is false, what is the main reason for it?",
    choice1: "Power failure",
    choice2: "The computer circuits",
    choice3: " Distraction",
    choice4: "Incorrect data entry",
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is extension of Windows Media Video File?",
    choice1: ".mv",
    choice2: ".wm",
    choice3: ".wmv",
    choice4: ".video",
    answer: 3,
  },
];